Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
12 Rick Doms from Admiral Dozle's
forces were eradicated...
...thanks to the teamwork of the
White Base crew.
However, their ship had to return
to Side 6 without being repaired...
...at the floating dock
outside the Side's airspace.
For the White Base,
there was no safe haven.
A Fateful Encounter
Welcome back. How did it go?
More formalities about our stay.
They want us out of here.
But... the Tianem Fleet
hasn't given us movement orders yet...
...and the enemy could be lying in wait.
When do you expect Amuro back?
In 2 hours.
Something important?
Yes... I'm quite sure it is.
Let's finish maintenance in three hours.
We're leaving.
Man! They could have at least
given me a weather schedule.
A bird.
Poor thing...
I-I'm sorry.
I didn't mean...
I didn't mean to scare you.
Uh... about that bird...
Were you fond of it?
Who could hate beautiful things?
...beautiful things?
Do you think there is anyone
who hates beautiful things?
Isn't it sad to watch them
grow old and perish?
Yeah. Sure it is...
But what I wanted to ask was...
Look! It's stopped raining.
Your eyes are so beautiful.
Yeah?
Are you sure we should leave
Conscon's group?
Can't be helped.
Vice Admiral Dozle and Conscon only
have their eyes on the immediate enemy.
That's not the case with Lady Kycilia.
She's looking at the direction
of the overall war.
Exactly what is at Side 6, Captain?
It'll be entering battle soon.
You'll find out then.
Let's enter the port.
Captain Char's Zanzibar
is docking at Side 6.
Char is...?!
Always doing whatever he pleases.
Now there's a big surprise!
We're docked in the same port
as an enemy warship.
It's a scene that could only happen
in a neutral Side.
It's like a comic book!
Why don't we invite the enemy over
and throw a party or something. Eh?
Right!
I just can't forgive them...!
Where are you going?!
What do you mean, "where"?
Mr. Ryu's killers are right in front of us!
Hayato!
You know what consequences we'd face
if we fought at this Side.
But still...!
We'll be departing very soon.
No one is to leave the ship!
There's a lot of maintenance to do still.
Everyone, to your stations now!
Damn it!
Just be sure you don't prolong
the duration of your stay.
Of course.
Now, the weapon seals...
I'm aware of the penalties.
Fine. And I don't want any trouble
with the Federation Forces.
I've already informed my men.
Thank you.
Is that so? I'm so happy
you've become the Gundam pilot.
The part I gave you last night!
How was it?
What...?
You know!
The new device I handed you!
It had tremendous effects... didn't it?
Amuro?
Oh. Yeah.
Of... course.
So, it worked great.
I'll develop more. And more!
I'll concentrate on new upgrades!
D-Dad...
It worked, did it?
Of course it did,
I made it after all.
My next one will be even...
D-Dad...
What good are shelter capsules, anyway?
Dad, are mobile suits more important
to you than human beings?
Send out the trailer!
Dad!
You go to the White Base, too!
Dad...
Oh no...
Damn you!
I shouldn't have taken the shortcut.
Excuse me!
Char?!
Sorry about that. Unfortunately,
the driver's still a novice.
S-Sure.
Sorry about that. I thought
you'd be able to dodge it.
We'll have to tow your car out.
Huh?
And you are...?
Amuro. I'm Amuro Ray.
Amuro...
It's strange... I feel as though
I've heard your name before.
Yes, I know you.
I know who you are.
I-I'll help you.
Relax. I'm done.
Thank you. Oh, um...
What's your name?
Char Aznable. I'm a soldier, as you can see.
Char!
Lalah! Step on the gas! But gently!
Yes, Captain.
So this is Char.
Char Aznable, he said.
Take it easy. Got it, Lalah?
What are you doing?
Stand back, Amuro.
I've never met him before.
So how did I know that he was Char?
And that girl...he called her Lalah.
How old are you?
Me? I'm 16.
Is that so? You're still young.
I can understand why you'd be nervous
in front of an enemy soldier.
But it would be nice if you
at least said thanks, Amuro?
Oh. Of course. Thank you very much.
I'd better go!
What was that boy so nervous about?
He probably recognized your name, Captain.
Char, the Red Comet.
He must have been afraid of you... I'm sure.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
The situation hasn't changed at all
since we arrived here.
No sense in worrying about it, Lieutenant.
Right. We send the Gundam out in front...
Excuse me.
Oh. We've been waiting for you.
You wanted something?
Actually... I was hoping
I could help you out personally.
Cameron...
What do you mean?
I have a private ship.
I can use it to escort you.
If a Side 6 ship were shielding you,
the Zeons couldn't open fire.
I do appreciate the thought, but...
Cameron. What do you expect
by doing that?
I'm shocked to hear you asking
such a question.
I'd rather you didn't interfere
in our business.
M-Mirai!
If you won't get off this ship,
then at least accept my help...!
If that's not interfering,
I don't know what is.
There's no need to be insulting!
You're just trying to convince me
that you can be helpful.
B-But you weren't there when I was
suffering the most. It's too late now!
But now I'm able to help you.
No, thank you!
You fool!
Lieutenant!
You!
This man is serious!
Understand?!
That's why he's offering to take this risk!
This may be a neutral Side...
...but one stray missile, and he's dead!
You understand?
And you...!
How can you stand there quietly
while she's hassling you like that?
There's no need to hit her. If we talked...
If you're serious, you'd have to!
That's so barbaric.
That's right, Mr. Cameron.
It's all about determination.
Right, Ensign?
Lieutenant Sleggar...
If you haven't changed your mind...
I would like to accept your offer.
Right. Please let me do this... Lieutenant.
Here they come.
But a Side 6 civilian ship is next to them.
It takes all kinds, I suppose.
- Have the Rick Doms launched?
- They should be ready now.
The Trojan Horse has changed course.
It's escaping in the opposite direction.
Deploy the Rick Doms at once!
Never mind airspace violations!
It will be fine!
The fighting will be outside the borders!
I can't stand being laughed at
by an upstart like Char.
This wasn't part of our deal!
You'll have to compensate me very well.
I know.
M-Mr. Cameron. We're already at the edge
of our airspace. If we go further...!
I know!
Whoa! They're coming!
They're here!
Bright! There are Zeon mobile suits!
Roger that!
You've done enough, Mr. Cameron.
No. Not until you leave our airspace...
in fact, we'll stay as long as we can fly.
Did something happen up on the bridge?
It's no concern for a kid.
I'll be at the main cannons.
Right.
Approaching Side 6 perimeter!
Mr. Cameron.
Lieutenant.
Please pull back.
We have no choice but to fight them.
Cameron... Thank you.
I'm grateful for your feelings.
However...!
Cameron, thank you.
Please go home...
Give my best to your father and mother.
M-Mirai.
I'm turning back.
Ugh!
Please! Fly by the bridge!
Open hatch!
Prepare to deploy the Gundam!
Guncannon and G-Fighter!
Stand by!
Here I go!
White Base, go to full combat speed!
Engaging in anti-air combat!
Yes, sir.
All right! Rick Doms,
commence the attack now.
Mega beam cannons, hold your fire!
Otherwise, stray beams might
enter Side 6.
It's started!
The battle's... started...
A TV crew!
M-Mirai.
J-Jamice!
You think you're so hot...!
Wait, Kai! Ignore the mobile suits!
All the main cannons need to do
is keep the enemy ship at bay.
Hit the enemy ships from the side!
Until then, use only
the missiles for defense.
You're not getting away!
Impossible!
It just can't be!
It's almost like he's predicting our moves!
No! It's just a fluke! Just luck.
Our only hope is to confuse him!
Let's use our favorite tactic!
Roger that!
I can see... how they'll move.
I see it!
This is not a TV drama.
This is actual combat.
The Federation and Zeon
are currently battling in outer space.
I'm not interested in the White Base!
Show me the Gundam!
Show me how it's doing in battle!
That's right. There!
Come on, Amuro!
What are you doing?!
Lieutenant! Enemy ahead!
Yeah, I know. Now just watch...
I repeat. This is a real battle.
The fighting is going on
just outside Side 6 borders.
The Federation's White Base
is fighting alone...
...against 3 Zeon ships.
Has Flanagan been treating you well?
Yes.
Watch this very carefully.
Real combat isn't nearly as
attractive as a TV drama.
As witnesses to this conflict...
...we must all give thought to the position
our nation should take in the future.
Why you...!
He fell for it!
Wait! Wait a second! I...!
What's happened?
Amuro's intuition is especially keen today.
I'm running out of energy!
If I can't use the beam rifle
I've got to switch to close combat!
This is ridiculous!
How can just one ship cause us
this much trouble?
Char is watching us! Char!
Ram into them!! Ram the Chivvay
right into the side of that Trojan Horse!
The Musais have been destroyed, and
the Chivvay heavy cruiser is advancing.
As there are no mobile suits in sight,
this battle is unpredictable.
The white mobile suit is going to win.
Hm? But the Gundam's not even on screen.
I can tell.
That's why you took a woman like me
under your wing, isn't it, Captain?
You're perceptive, Lalah.
They're ramming us.
It's proof that they're getting desperate.
Where's their vital spot?
There!
Enemy below!
What?!
No! Portside!
Left?!
See, Captain?
That's right!
Way to go, Amuro!
It's all thanks to my new device!
The Gundam's the real deal!
Hooray for the Earth Federation!
We can head back now.
Sure thing.
Please make it through this...
Side... 6...
The Earth Federation Forces stage
a full-scale attack...
...against Space Fortress Solomon.
At the vanguard of the Tianem Fleet,
the White Base cuts through the enemy.
For the first time, Amuro and the crew
risk their lives in the middle of a battlefield.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
The Glory of Solomon
Will you be able to survive?
Next Time
The Glory of Solomon
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...